

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Monterrev. NL. México

🛘 (+52) 8114140740 | 🔀 danielcardeenas@gmail.com | 🏕 danielcardeenas.github.io | 🖸 danielcardeenas | 🖹 danielcardeenas

## Summary.

Full-stack developer with 10+ years of experience in building web apps and systems. I am interested in working on Supply Chain, Logistics, Concurrency, High performance, Beautiful UI/UX and B2B applications.

I like to do open-source projects in my freetime that involve Automation, HFT, Kafka, Aeron, Frontend development, Whatsapp chatbots.

## Work Experience and Freelancing

Luxoft Remote | Sunnyvale, CA

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2022 - Current

- Lead development of NextJS/React solutions, delivering timely and robust web applications for multi-site laboratory protein tracking.
- Analyze and optimize web applications, improving data tracking accuracy for laboratory proteins across multiple locations.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to develop NextJS/React web apps, streamlining protein tracking processes at various job sites.

Genie Terex Remote | Monterrey, MX

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2022 - 2022

- Genie Machines: Enhanced machine software with C++, fixing bugs and ensuring reliable code support for Genie Machines
- · Conducted rigorous code reviews and debugging sessions to ensure high-quality, reliable machine software performance.
- Implemented efficient code solutions and bug fixes, enhancing overall software functionality and user experience.

Cemex (Neoris).

Prague, CZ | Remote | Monterrey, MX

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER (FRONTEND)

2016 - 2022

- Implemented Track & Trace with Google Maps API in **Angular**, boosting delivery tracking accuracy.
- · Led Orders & Products module development in Angular and React, enhancing client purchasing in 20+ countries
- Developed Employee Console in Angular, automating contract and order management for Cemex employees

Stukent (Freelance) Idaho, US | Remote

(INDEPENDENT) FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

2021 - 2022

- Developed and deployed modular Coursware components using Storybook, ensuring seamless integration and functionality through rigorous
  Jest testing.
- Managed **Azure** functions in C# for data handling in simulations, ensuring seamless operations.

1EQ. (Freelance) Washington, DC | Remote

(INDEPENDENT) FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

2019 - 2020

• Healthcare Babyscripts: Maternity care platform.

Each feature development involving all the layers of development. Frontend with **Angular** for Hospitals and providers web app and Hybrid application for patients. Everything is built with **Webpack** 

Backend using mostly AWS (DynamoDB, Lambda, SQS, SNS), GraphQL. Also Iterable for campaigns connections and notifications

#### Mi Chance (Manufacture Freelance)

Remote | Mérida, MX | Monterrey, MX

(INDEPENDENT) SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2016 - 2017

- Developed every layer of a **Google Cloud-based system**, ensuring high performance and cost efficiency through auto-scaling compute engines.
- Developed frontend applications in Kotlin (Native) and Angular (Web), enhancing user experience and traffic management.
- Utilized Datastore as the primary NoSQL database to ensure cost-effectiveness and performance.

OXXO Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE & LEAD DEVELOPER

2014 - 2016

- Designed and implemented a kiosk system for OXXO stores, enhancing POS connectivity and uptime. Using iOS native development **Swift** and **Objective-C**. Programmed entire UI from given designs from the UI team
- Led the design and deployment of a 24/7 self-updating kiosk system, enhancing POS integration and operational efficiency across select Oxxo
- Designed the DB (MySQL) for flexibility using resources already provided by the OXXO Stores.
- · Transmitted the order via FTP with to the physical POS. Printed the order ticket for the end user via Bluetooth using printer SDK

Epicor Software Corp Monterrey, MX

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

2012 - 2014

- Supported and customized CRM 'Clientele' in .NET, enhancing functionality and user experience.
- Contributed to the development of web ERP 'P21' using ASP MVC, improving system efficiency.
- Developed software in C# and SQL, ensuring robust and scalable solutions.

July 8, 2024 Daniel Cardenas · Résumé

## **Projects**

### **PROJECTS**

2014	Audio Stego, Stenography tool. Built in C++.	Home	
2016	🗘 QuandlCpp, Efficient Quandl C++ library	Home	
2017	Old Whatsapp framework, Python framework for whatsapp bots creation. Built in Python.		
2017	🗘 leind-stocks , Scraps data from Quandl, Yahoo finance, etc To do the fundamental analysis explained in	Hamaa	
	the William O'Neil book. Drops similar results to the IDB Leaderboard. Built in C++.	Home	
2019	Sulla, Sulla is a javascript library which provides a high-level API control to Whatsapp so it can be configured to automatize resposes or any data that goes trough Whatsapp effortlessly.	Home	

#### **FREELANCER**

2016	Quandl retriver (tecenergy.ca), Quandl big data retriever for data science firm active in financial	Montreal, CA
	electricity markets. Built in C# and PostgreSQL.	Montreut, CA
	<b>Profet CRM (Full-stack)</b> , Created of custom CRM system that was later sold to this company so their	
2016	developers can maintain it and develop above it. The stack usedfor this application is mainly .NET Core and	Remote
	it's deployed into Azure.	
	<b>% Ion Water distributor ERP (Full-stack),</b> Developed a whole custom ERP system from scratch.	
2014 - '16	Architecture of the application is based on modules which are easily added to the systemas the client needs.	Damata
	This system is deployed into the client servers which used IIS. and still running. The stack used here is T-SQL,	Remote

## Ski**lls**\_\_\_\_

Frontend	Angular   React   Vue   Vanilla JS   NextJS
Programming	TS   JS   Python   C++   Rust   Java   C#
Distributed programming	Kafka   Aeron   Vertx   Java
Backend	NodeJS   .NET Core   SQL   NoSQL   HFT
DevOps	Azure   AWS   Google Cloud Services
Automatization	Jest   Mocha   Puppeteer

# Languages I speak \_

.NET MVC.

Spanish Fluent, English Fluent, Italian Intermediate,

## Education

### UANL - Facultad de Ciencias Físico Matemáticas

Monterrey, MX

Monterrey, MX

California, US

2023

PHYSICS

• Study of the fundamental principles of physics, including mechanics, electromagnetism, thermodynamics, and quantum mechanics.

## UANL - Facultad de Ingeniería Mecánica Eléctrica

Aug. 2011 - Exp. Nov. 2015

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

· Study of software development principles, algorithms, data structures, and programming languages. Specialized in web development and cloud computing.

### **Acceleration program**

Sep. 2015 - Nov. 2015

• Developed a mobile app to help people find places. Daily workshops focused on how produce a fast app launching for startups, marketing, innovation, etc...

## Machine Learning A-Z™: Hands-On Python & R In Data Science

Remote

UDEMY

PLUG & PLAY

• Machine learning course